Gina Quistiano Zavala 322 N Dalton Ave Azusa, Ca 91702

Cell: 559-960-6530 ginaz | 13@hotmail.com

Profile

I have twelve+ years of archaeological lab and fieldwork work in North America and the Caribbean with an M.A. in Maritime Archaeology of the Caribbean from Indiana University, Bloomington. This includes three years of supervisory experience at various field schools in North America and eight years of experience as an archaeological technician in California from 2000-2005 and again in 2009, 2015 and 2016. I have broad experience in all phases of Cultural Resource Management including survey, excavation, construction monitoring, artifact analysis, regional research and report writing from work on both historic and prehistoric sites.

Education

M.A. Archaeology. Emphasis: Caribbean Maritime Archaeology
Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

May 2000

B.A. Anthropology with an emphasis in Archaeology, University of California – Berkeley

Minor German Language, University of California - Berkeley

June 1999, July 2000

Archaeological Field School in Cave Archaeology in Belize, (BVAR) University of New Hampshire

Archaeological Field School in Underwater Archaeology in Bermuda, St. Mary's College, Moraga, California

Fluency in Spanish, German and Haitian Creole CPR and First Aid Training

Career History

July 2015-Present

Evans and De Shazo Archaeology and Historic Preservation, Sebastopol, CA

Laboratory Analysis

September 2009

EC Environmental, Ardsley, NY

Technician. Archaeological Testing and Report writing for telecommunication projects, completed 2009.

Arch 2, Metuchen, NJ

Technician. Completed Testing for a Phase I county development project completed 2009.

Graduate Student Assistant in an underwater archaeology field school in the Dominican Republic with Indiana University. Assessed and curated historic, cultural and natural resources on the

Guadalupe Underwater Park in *Bayahibe* and supervised students at an underwater field school at the site of *La Isabela*, Columbus's first settlement in the Americas.

Graduate Student Supervisor for the Big Horn Mountain/ Plains Archaeology Field school with Dr. Laura Scheiber at Indiana

May 2005, June-August 2006, June-July 2007 University. Helped direct the field schools over 3 seasons in Wyoming, Montana and Nebraska to survey, map and excavate at Shoshone Tipi Ring sites, Big Horn Sheep Hunting traps and drive lines in the Absaroka Mountains.

Associate Instructor for the IU Department of Anthropology Topics Courses: The Rise and Fall of Ancient Civilizations and Lost Tribes and Sunken Continents with Dr. King and Dr. Pyburn, respectively. Led five discussion sections total, graded exams, papers and quizzes as well as assisted in course development.

Aug 2006-May 2007

William Self Associates. Archaeological Technician, Orinda, CA

June-October 2001 and 2004

Excavation in the Mojave Desert –BLM HWY 395 Expansion 2001, Hercules Homes Development on Bay Boulevard 2001, Pinole Valley Park 2004, and Emeryville Shell Mound at the Bay St Development 2004. I monitored construction at archeological sites from Concord to Sacramento on the Kinder Morgan Pipeline Project 2004. I also performed lab duties such as soil screening and artifact analysis.

Archaeological Resource Service. Archaeological Technician, Petaluma, CA

October 2001-June 2004

I participated in phases I,II and III on several projects. I helped to survey, monitor, excavate and analyze CRM findings on public and private lands as well as contributed and independently completed final CRM reports concerning archaeological sites in San Francisco: Letterman Digital Arts Studio 2002, Marin: 10 N. Pt. Circle, MRN 39 2001-2003, completed 2003, Sonoma-Surveys in 2002, Napa: Vineyard Surveys in 2003 Santa Clara: Avignon Housing Development 2003, completed 2003, Skyport Development Project 2003 and Lake County survey and excavation 2003.

Holman and Associates. Archaeological Technician, San Francisco, CA

January 2001-June 2001

Excavated sites in Amador: Jackson Rancheria Casino -2001 and Santa Clara Counties-Housing Development 2001 and monitored archeological sites in Santa Clara County.

December 2000 and May 2002

Applied Earthworks. Archaeological Technician Fresno and Hemet, CA Excavated in McNamee Cave in Stanislaus Co. CA-2000 and

performed survey in Big Bear, CA 2002

August
-December 2001

Management Cultural Resources. Riverside CA Monitored Construction in La Quinta, CA

June-August 2000

Pacific Legacy. Archaeological Technician, Albany, CA.

Excavated at archaeological sites in Palo Alto at the Stanford Ronald McDonald House 2000 and on Stanford Campus at the historic residences 2000 with supervisor Ellie Reese.

April -June 2000

Archaeor. Archaeological Technician, Pleasanton, CA. Excavated at archaeological sites in Fremont at City Hall April 2000, Pleasanton Chevy Dealership Expansion on Thornton Valley Road 2001